<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other | Open Neuroscience</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/category/other/</link><atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/category/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Other</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url><title>Other</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/category/other/</link></image><item><title>BigPint Bioconductor package that makes BIG (RNA seq) data pint sized</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bigpint_bioconductor_package_that_makes_big_rna_seq_data_pint_sized/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/bigpint_bioconductor_package_that_makes_big_rna_seq_data_pint_sized/</guid><description>&lt;p>The BigPint package can help examine any large multivariate dataset. However, we note that the example datasets and example code in this package consider RNA-sequencing datasets. If you are using this software for RNA-sequencing data, then it can help you confirm that the variability between your treatment groups is larger than that between your replicates and determine how various normalization techniques in popular RNA-sequencing analysis packages (such as edgeR, DESeq2, and limma) affect your dataset. Moreover, you can easily superimpose lists of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) onto your dataset to check that they show the expected patterns (large variability between treatment groups and small variability between replicates).&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>BigPint software website: &lt;a href="https://lindsayrutter.github.io/bigPint/">https://lindsayrutter.github.io/bigPint/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Article explaining the BigPint methodology: &lt;a href="https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-019-2968-1">https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-019-2968-1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Research article showcasing the BigPint software:
&lt;a href="https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-019-5767-1">https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-019-5767-1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Article explaining the BigPint software: &lt;a href="https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007912">https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007912&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lindsay Rutter; Dianne Cook&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lindsayrutter/bigPint">https://github.com/lindsayrutter/bigPint&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>jsPsych</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/jspsych/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/jspsych/</guid><description>&lt;p>jsPsych is a JavaScript library for running behavioral experiments in a web browser. The library provides a flexible framework for building a wide range of laboratory-like experiments that can be run online. To use jsPsych, you provide a description of the experiment in the form of a timeline. jsPsych handles things like determining which trial to run next, storing data, and randomization. jsPsych uses plugins to define what to do at each point on the timeline. Plugins are ready-made templates for simple experimental tasks like displaying instructions or displaying a stimulus and collecting a keyboard response. Plugins are very flexible to support a wide variety of experiments. It is easy to create your own plugin if you have experience with JavaScript programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Josh de Leeuw&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.jspsych.org">https://www.jspsych.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Psygo</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psygo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psygo/</guid><description>&lt;p>The easiest way to get started creating online behavioural experiments! psygo is a CLI tool that streamlines the development of custom jsPsych plugins, allowing you to create custom behavioural experiments that can be run online. psygo also helps you test your experiment locally. All the hard work is done for you, from setting up a project, to preparing it for administration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Henry Burgess&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/henry-burgess/psygo">https://github.com/henry-burgess/psygo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Henry Burgess&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Brain Explained</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brain_explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brain_explained/</guid><description>&lt;p>Brain Explained explores the latest neuroscience that is fresh of the press. Tune in each month to listen to a deep dive interview into a research paper or thesis with the researcher. Gain an understanding of what its like to be a researcher at the cutting edge and an understanding of the brain at the molecular level.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Abdullah Iqbal&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://anchor.fm/brain-explained">https://anchor.fm/brain-explained&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Abdullah Iqbal&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>INCF KnowledgeSpace</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_knowledgespace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_knowledgespace/</guid><description>&lt;p>KnowledgeSpace aims to be a globally-used, community-based, data-driven encyclopedia for neuroscience that links brain research concepts to data, models, and the literature that support them. Further it aims to serve as a framework where large-scale neuroscience projects can expose their data to the neuroscience community-at-large. KnowledgeSpace is a framework that combines general descriptions of neuroscience concepts found in wikipedia with more detailed content from NeuroLex. It then integrates the content from those two sources with the latest neuroscience citations found in PubMed and data found in some of the world’s leading neuroscience repositories. KnowledgeSpace is a joint development between the Human Brain Project (HBP), the International Neuroinformatics Coordinating Facility (INCF), and the Neuroscience Information Framework (NIF).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KnowledgeSpace is currently being developed with funding from the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Framework Programme for Research and Innovation under the Specific Grant Agreement No. 945539 (Human Brain Project SGA3), INCF, and Neuroscience Information Framework (NIF). Earlier development was supported by the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Framework Programme for Research and Innovation under the Framework Partnership Agreement No. 650003 (HBP FPA), INCF, NIF, and the Blue Brain Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KS builds on a vocabulary service, populated with an integrated set of neuroscience ontologies with initial content coming from the Neuroscience Lexicon (NeuroLex), and the Brain Architecture Management System (BAMS). It links to an expanding set of data sources through the NIF federated search infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>INCF team&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://knowledge-space.org">https://knowledge-space.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQCGZOPLED0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQCGZOPLED0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>brainrender</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brainrender/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brainrender/</guid><description>&lt;p>brainrender is a python package for the visualization of three dimensional neuro-anatomical data. It can be used to render data from publicly available data set (e.g. Allen Brain atlas) as well as user generated experimental data. The goal of brainrender is to facilitate the exploration and dissemination of neuro-anatomical data by providing a user-friendly platform to create high-quality 3D renderings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Federico Claudi&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/BrancoLab/BrainRender">https://github.com/BrancoLab/BrainRender&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Federico Claudi&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>PiDose</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/pidose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/pidose/</guid><description>&lt;p>PiDose is an open-source tool for scientists performing drug administration experiments with mice. It allows for automated daily oral dosing of mice over long time periods (weeks to months) without the need for experimenter interaction and handling. To accomplish this, a small 3D-printed chamber is mounted adjacent to a regular mouse home-cage, with an opening in the cage to allow animals to freely access the chamber.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chamber is supported by a load cell, and does not contact the cage but sits directly next to the entrance opening. Prior to treatment, mice have a small RFID capsule implanted subcutaneously, and when they enter the chamber they are detected by an RFID reader. While the mouse is in the chamber, readings are taken from the load cell in order to determine the mouse&amp;rsquo;s bodyweight. At the opposite end of the chamber from the entrance, a nose-poke port accesses a spout which dispenses drops from two separate liquid reservoirs. This spout is wired to a capacitive touch sensor controller in order to detect licks, and delivers liquid drops in response to licking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each day, an average weight is calculated for each mouse and a drug dosage is determined based on this. When a mouse licks at the spout it dispenses either regular drinking water or a drop of drug solution depending on if they have received their daily dosage or not. All components are controlled by a Python script running on a Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cameron Woodard; Wissam Nasrallah; Bahram Samiei; Tim Murphy; Lynn Raymond&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://osf.io/rpyfm/">https://osf.io/rpyfm/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Cameron Woodard&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>An Open-source Anthropomorphic Robot Hand System: HRI Hand</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/an_open-source_anthropomorphic_robot_hand_system_hri_hand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/an_open-source_anthropomorphic_robot_hand_system_hri_hand/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present an open-source anthropomorphic robot hand system called HRI hand. Our robot hand system was developed with a focus on the end-effector role of the collaborative robot manipulator. HRI hand is a research platform that can be built at a lower price (approximately $500, using only 3D printing) than commercial end-effectors. Moreover, it was designed as a two four-bar linkage for the under-actuated mechanism and provides pre-shaping motion similar to the human hand prior to touching an object. A URDF, python node, and rviz package is also provided to support the Robot Operating System (ROS). All hardware CAD design files and software source codes have been released and can be easily assembled and modified. The system proposed in this paper is developed with a five-finger structure, but each finger is modularized, so it can be developed with end-effectors of various shapes depending on the shape of the palm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hyeonjun Park; Donghan Kim&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/MrLacuqer/HRI-hand-firmware.git">https://github.com/MrLacuqer/HRI-hand-firmware.git&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/c5Ry3tl9FVw">https://youtu.be/c5Ry3tl9FVw&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Andre M Chagas&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>SciDraw</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/scidraw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/scidraw/</guid><description>&lt;p>SciDraw is a free repository of high quality drawings of animals, scientific setups, and anything that might be useful for scientific presentations and posters.
We want this repository to be as open as possible, so do not require signing up to post a drawing. This however means that you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to edit your drawings after submission, so upload carefully!
The drawings on SciDraw are made by and for scientists. You are free to download, modify and use all drawings on the website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Federico Claudi and Alex Harston&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://scidraw.io/">https://scidraw.io/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Matias Andina&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Neuroanatomy and Behaviour</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neuroanatomy_and_behaviour/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/neuroanatomy_and_behaviour/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neuroanatomy and Behaviour (ISSN: 2652-1768) is a free open access journal for behavioural neuroscience and related fields. Powered by free open source software to eliminate costs and keep grant funds doing science. Scientist-run and non-profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Episteme Health Inc.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://epistemehealth.com">https://epistemehealth.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Shaun Khoo&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Crowd funding</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/crowd-funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/crowd-funding/</guid><description>&lt;p>As many other things that are being decentralized with the advent of the internet, so is research. One of the very things being decentralized is the funding source for research projects. This movement is called crowdfunding, and it is already present and strong for other areas, such as funding of technological, and social projects. They are organized via specialised websites that puts people needing funding with people who are willing to support it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea is somewhat simple. Researchers make a video of what their project/research idea is and ask for a certain value to fund the project. If people find the idea interesting they make a donation via the website hosting that project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are normally two types of funding options, fixed, where the researchers only get the money pledged if the donations reach that value (or pass it, and if the minimum is not reached the money is returned to the pledgers), or variable where the researchers get to keep the money raised even if it didn’t reach the amount pledged for. In both cases the website keeps a percentage of the money raised in case the funding is successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Articles about it can be founded &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/higher-education-network/blog/2013/nov/11/science-research-funding-crowdfunding-excellence" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.nyas.org/publications/EBriefings/Detail.aspx?cid=82c4e4b4-f200-49b3-b333-c41e1e2f46aa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some crowdfunding sources are listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sciencestarter.de/">http://www.sciencestarter.de/&lt;/a> – Research crowdfunding portal based in germany&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://experiment.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.microryza.com/&lt;/a> – Research crowdFunding portal based in the US. (update – this is now called experiment.com)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/?ref=nav" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.kickstarter.com&lt;/a> – A Crowdfunding portal that also works for science projects. Currently (as in 02.02.14) only for projects based on the US, Canada, UK, Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.indiegogo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.indiegogo.com&lt;/a> Also a crowdfunding portal that has science related projects. Differently from kickstarter, they support projects from all over the world, except countries in the US OFAC sanctions list&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/">https://www.crowdsupply.com/&lt;/a> is another crowdfunding portal, based in the US, that focus on product development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ulule.com/">http://www.ulule.com/&lt;/a> – A crowdfunding portal based in Europe. They have a nice post on &lt;a href="http://blog.ulule.com/post/700805254/a-brief-history-of-crowdfunding?_ga=1.104969667.1799200825.1396358648" target="_blank" rel="noopener">crowdfunding history&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.petridish.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.petridish.org&lt;/a> Research crowdfunding portal, but it seems that they haven’t been taking new projects for a while (since February 2013)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;del>&lt;a href="http://sciflies.org/about">&lt;a href="http://www.sciflies.org">www.sciflies.org&lt;/a>&lt;/a> – Research crowdfunding portal based in Florida, their differential is that all projects posted there have to be approved by an anonymous peer review process, currently done by the American Association for Advancement of science. And 100% of the money goes to the project, there are no administrative fees. It was not clear from the website if only US based projects are funded&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.rockethub.com/">http://www.rockethub.com/&lt;/a> – General crowdfunding portal, that has also a science division where everyone can start a project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://scifundchallenge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scifundchallenge.org&lt;/a> – Built and maintained by the &lt;a href="http://opensciencefederation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">open science federation&lt;/a>, this project has three main “departments”, all trying to bridge the gap in between science and the general public: Teach and encourage scientists to outreach, connect the public directly with scientists and science crowdfund.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interesting projects</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/other-interesting-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/other-interesting-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is great that there are other interesting projects out there that are also concerned with making science available to more people! Here is a short list of projects I came across. They are not necessarily focusing on open source, but worth getting to know anyhow:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://trendinafrica.org/who-are-we/our-mission/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TReND in Africa&lt;/a>: Where TReND stands for Teaching and Research in Neuroscience for Development, is a initiative to stop the brain drain in sub-Saharan Africa. They are a non-profit organisation led by a small group of researchers that are training and teaching local African scientists. On top of that they also coordinate the collection of money and equipment donation to establish permanent research facilities on African universities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/cbonsig/open-stent" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Stent project&lt;/a>: Although more into medicine rather than neuroscience is the open stent project is developed by &lt;a href="http://www.nitinol.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NDC&lt;/a>. Their stent was first designed to aid customer interaction. It seems that when giving examples on design improvements, they would always bump into proprietary issues, therefore they developed their own design and made the blueprints available for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/GliaX/Stethoscope" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open source stethoscope:&lt;/a> This is a 3D printed stethoscope, developed by Tarek Loubani, a doctor that works in Gaza and with a 3D printer and 5 dollars worth of materials (tubes, ear piece and plastic to be printed) he and his group were able to outperform the Littmann Cardiology 3, a market leader, that sells for over 20X the price of the printed one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://hackteria.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackteria&lt;/a> – Is a wiki page that collects several DIY projects related to Biology and Open Source Art Projects that use Biology, LifeSciences, Biotechnology. Among the projects listed are centrifuges, water baths, field microscopes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.appropedia.org/Open-source_Lab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Source Lab:&lt;/a>   A project by Prof. Joshua Pearce of Michigan University. It advocates in favour of researchers building their own lab equipment using 3D printers and other “off the shelf” available items. Although the main focus of the lab are environmental problems, a lot of the solutions there stated can easily be harvested/modified for neuroscience purposes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.cooking-hacks.com/documentation/tutorials/ehealth-biometric-sensor-platform-arduino-raspberry-pi-medical" target="_blank" rel="noopener">e-Health sensor platform&lt;/a>: A device created at the open source division of Libelium, called cooking hacks. It allows integration of several health related sensors (blood pressure, oxygen level, glucose level, muscle activity, airflow, galvanic response) into arduino and raspberry pi. Which can be used to make real time monitoring of patients and/or test subjects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.bitalino.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitalino&lt;/a>: On the same lines as e-health (above), the Bitalino is a complete platform for measurements of biosignals, but this project is more focused on learning and prototyping. It also has free software for data visualization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://littledevices.org/research/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Little Devices&lt;/a>: develops tools to improve health care and diagnostics. They are open source, and DIY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://publiclab.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Public lab&lt;/a>: Involved with environmental issues, Public lab is a platform that empowers communities to measure environmental variables around them. This way hard data concerning water, air and soil pollution can be used to put pressure on governments.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1606.01196" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open source Muon Detector:&lt;/a> an undergraduate-level physics project that incorporates various aspects of machine- and electronics-shop technical development. The desktop muon detector is a self-contained apparatus that employs plastic scintillator as a detection medium and a silicon photomultiplier for light collection. These detectors can be used in conjunction with the provided software to make interesting physics measurements. The total cost of each counter is approximately $100.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Open lab notebooks</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open-lab-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open-lab-notebooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_notebook_science" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open notebooks&lt;/a> are opening up science in the very first steps, making records of ideas, plans that didn’t work and protocols that failed available publicly. This allows others to avoid trailing the same dead end roads, saving time, money and human power. Some examples are listed below, but unfortunately there weren’t enough examples in the neuroscience field (until 22/01/14), so examples from all fields are listed:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://carlboettiger.info/lab-notebook.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Carl Boettiger’s notebook&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.jeremiahfaith.com/open_notebook_science/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jeremiah Faith’s notebook&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/michaelbarton" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michael Barton’s github repository&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>