<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Human Neuroscience | Open Neuroscience</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/tag/human-neuroscience/</link><atom:link href="https://open-neuroscience.com/tag/human-neuroscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Human Neuroscience</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY SA 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://open-neuroscience.com/media/openneuroscience_logo_dark.svg</url><title>Human Neuroscience</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/tag/human-neuroscience/</link></image><item><title>jsPsych</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/jspsych/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/jspsych/</guid><description>&lt;p>jsPsych is a JavaScript library for running behavioral experiments in a web browser. The library provides a flexible framework for building a wide range of laboratory-like experiments that can be run online. To use jsPsych, you provide a description of the experiment in the form of a timeline. jsPsych handles things like determining which trial to run next, storing data, and randomization. jsPsych uses plugins to define what to do at each point on the timeline. Plugins are ready-made templates for simple experimental tasks like displaying instructions or displaying a stimulus and collecting a keyboard response. Plugins are very flexible to support a wide variety of experiments. It is easy to create your own plugin if you have experience with JavaScript programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Josh de Leeuw&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.jspsych.org">https://www.jspsych.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Psygo</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psygo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/psygo/</guid><description>&lt;p>The easiest way to get started creating online behavioural experiments! psygo is a CLI tool that streamlines the development of custom jsPsych plugins, allowing you to create custom behavioural experiments that can be run online. psygo also helps you test your experiment locally. All the hard work is done for you, from setting up a project, to preparing it for administration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Henry Burgess&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/henry-burgess/psygo">https://github.com/henry-burgess/psygo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Henry Burgess&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Brain Explained</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brain_explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/brain_explained/</guid><description>&lt;p>Brain Explained explores the latest neuroscience that is fresh of the press. Tune in each month to listen to a deep dive interview into a research paper or thesis with the researcher. Gain an understanding of what its like to be a researcher at the cutting edge and an understanding of the brain at the molecular level.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Abdullah Iqbal&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://anchor.fm/brain-explained">https://anchor.fm/brain-explained&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Abdullah Iqbal&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Collaborative Informatics and Neuroimaging Suite Toolkit for Anonymous Computation (COINSTAC)</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/collaborative_informatics_and_neuroimaging_suite_toolkit_for_anonymous_computation_coinstac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/collaborative_informatics_and_neuroimaging_suite_toolkit_for_anonymous_computation_coinstac/</guid><description>&lt;p>COINSTAC provides a platform to analyze data stored locally across multiple organizations without the need for pooling the data at any point during the analysis. It is intended to be an ultimate one-stop shop by which researchers can build any statistical or machine learning model collaboratively in a decentralized fashion. This framework implements a message passing infrastructure that will allow large scale analysis of decentralized data with results on par with those that would have been obtained if the data were in one place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sergey M. Plis; Anand D. Sarwate; Dylan Wood; Christopher Dieringer; Drew Landis; Cory Reed; Sandeep R. Panta; Jessica A. Turner; Jody M. Shoemaker; Kim W. Carter; Paul Thompson; Kent Hutchison; Vince D. Calhoun&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/trendscenter/coinstac">https://github.com/trendscenter/coinstac&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Kelly Rootes-Murdy&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>ERPLAB</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/erplab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/erplab/</guid><description>&lt;p>ERPLAB Toolbox is a free, open-source Matlab package for analyzing ERP data. It is tightly integrated with EEGLAB Toolbox, extending EEGLAB’s capabilities to provide robust, industrial-strength tools for ERP processing, visualization, and analysis. A graphical user interface makes it easy for beginners to learn, and Matlab scripting provides enormous power for intermediate and advanced users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Andrew X Stewart; Steve Luck&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/lucklab/erplab">https://github.com/lucklab/erplab&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Andrew X Stewart&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Computational Cognitive Neuroscience 4th Ed</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/computational_cognitive_neuroscience_4th_ed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/computational_cognitive_neuroscience_4th_ed/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the 4th edition of the online, freely available textbook, providing a complete, self-contained introduction to the field of Computational Cognitive Neuroscience, where computer models of the brain are used to understand a wide range of cognitive functions, including perception, attention, motor control, learning, memory, language, and executive function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first part of this textbook develops a coherent set of computational and neural principles that capture the behavior of networks of interconnected neurons, and the second part applies these principles to understand the above-listed cognitive functions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Randall C. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly; Yuko Munakata; Michael J. Frank; Thomas E. Hazy&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://compcogneuro.org">https://compcogneuro.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Randall C. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Emergent Neural Network Simulation Software</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/emergent_neural_network_simulation_software/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/emergent_neural_network_simulation_software/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neural network simulation software written in Go and Python, for developing biologically-based but also computationally functional neural models. Features an interactive 3D interface for visualizing networks and data, and has many implemented models of a wide range of cognitive phenomena.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Randall C. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/emer/emergent">https://github.com/emer/emergent&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Randall C. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>EmotiBit</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/emotibit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/emotibit/</guid><description>&lt;p>EmotiBit is a wearable sensor to capture high-quality emotional, physiological, and movement data from just about anywhere on the body.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sean Montgomery&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.emotibit.com/">https://www.emotibit.com/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbcL2jzyWj4&amp;amp;ab_channel=EmotiBit">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbcL2jzyWj4&amp;amp;ab_channel=EmotiBit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Sean Montgomery&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>INCF KnowledgeSpace</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_knowledgespace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_knowledgespace/</guid><description>&lt;p>KnowledgeSpace aims to be a globally-used, community-based, data-driven encyclopedia for neuroscience that links brain research concepts to data, models, and the literature that support them. Further it aims to serve as a framework where large-scale neuroscience projects can expose their data to the neuroscience community-at-large. KnowledgeSpace is a framework that combines general descriptions of neuroscience concepts found in wikipedia with more detailed content from NeuroLex. It then integrates the content from those two sources with the latest neuroscience citations found in PubMed and data found in some of the world’s leading neuroscience repositories. KnowledgeSpace is a joint development between the Human Brain Project (HBP), the International Neuroinformatics Coordinating Facility (INCF), and the Neuroscience Information Framework (NIF).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KnowledgeSpace is currently being developed with funding from the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Framework Programme for Research and Innovation under the Specific Grant Agreement No. 945539 (Human Brain Project SGA3), INCF, and Neuroscience Information Framework (NIF). Earlier development was supported by the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Framework Programme for Research and Innovation under the Framework Partnership Agreement No. 650003 (HBP FPA), INCF, NIF, and the Blue Brain Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KS builds on a vocabulary service, populated with an integrated set of neuroscience ontologies with initial content coming from the Neuroscience Lexicon (NeuroLex), and the Brain Architecture Management System (BAMS). It links to an expanding set of data sources through the NIF federated search infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>INCF team&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://knowledge-space.org">https://knowledge-space.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQCGZOPLED0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQCGZOPLED0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>INCF NeuroStars</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_neurostars/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_neurostars/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neurostars is an open source question and answer site that serves the INCF network and the global neuroscience community as a forum for knowledge exchange between neuroscience researchers at all levels of expertise, software developers, and infrastructure providers. Access to Neurostars is free to the neuroscience community thanks to the generous support of our sponsors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neurostars is a forum for research questions, software, infrastructure, scientific societies, and virtual courses, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software developers and infrastructure providers in need of a mechanism in which to engage and provide support to user communities and those in need of a platform to integrate tutorials and discussion forums (via INCF TrainingSpace)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scientific societies in need of a forum for knowledge exchange and support between members&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Virtual course organizers in need of an archivable Q &amp;amp; A forum to support learning in their courses where access can be restricted to registered participants with automated notifications and the ability to have multiple, linked subdiscussion groups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Individuals in need of sharing ideas, asking questions and finding answers, and helping others within neuroscience without any cost&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>INCF team&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://neurostars.org">https://neurostars.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veVD1olyaW4&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>INCF Portal</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_portal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_portal/</guid><description>&lt;p>The INCF portal is the guide to the INCF activities and its community resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INCF advances data reuse and reproducibility in brain research by coordinating the development of Open, FAIR, and Citable tools and resources for neuroscience&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The global INCF network&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>supports the development of neuroinformatics as a discipline&lt;/li>
&lt;li>moves neuroscience towards FORCE (a FAIR, Open, Research-object based, Citable Ecosystem)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>provides coordination of global neuroscience infrastructure through the development and endorsement of consensus-based standards and best practices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>trains scientists, administrators, and students in using neuroinformatics tools and methods&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>INCF provides materials, expertise, training, and standards and best practices for: 1) scientists seeking to improve their science through neuroinformatics, 2) infrastructure providers so they can do their jobs better and participate in the global network, and 3) those seeking to add their tools, services, and expertise to the INCF network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>INCF currently has Governing and Associate Nodes spanning 4 continents, with an extended network comprising organizations, individual researchers, industry, and publishers. The INCF Secretariat supports the Nodes with outreach, project management, and administration of community-driven projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can join the INCF network: &lt;a href="https://www.incf.org/join-incf">https://www.incf.org/join-incf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>INCF team&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.incf.org">https://www.incf.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=teFJ_W6nVUY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=teFJ_W6nVUY&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>INCF TrainingSpace</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_trainingspace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/incf_trainingspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>TrainingSpace is an online hub that aims to make neuroscience educational materials more accessible to the global neuroscience community developed by the Training and Education Committee composed of members from the INCF network, HBP, SfN, FENS, IBRO, IEEE, BD2K, and iNeuro Initiative. As a hub, TrainingSpace provides users with access to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Multimedia educational content from courses, conference lectures, and laboratory exercises from some of the world’s leading neuroscience institutes and societies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Study tracks to facilitate self-guided study&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tutorials on tools and open science resources for neuroscience research&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Q&amp;amp;A forum&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A neuroscience encyclopedia that provides users with access to over 1.000.000 publicly available datasets as well as links to literature references and scientific abstracts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Topics currently included in TrainingSpace include: general neuroscience, clinical neuroscience, computational neuroscience, neuroinformatics, computer science, data science, and open science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All courses and conference lectures in TrainingSpace include a general description, topics covered, links to prerequisite courses if applicable, and links to software described in or required for the course, as well as links to the next lecture in the course or more advanced related courses. In addition to providing resources for students and researchers, TrainingSpace also provides resources for instructors, such laboratory exercises, open science services, and access to publicly available datasets and models.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>INCF team&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://training.incf.org">https://training.incf.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHnW0z2qeQE&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Malin Sandström&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Open Source Brain</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open_source_brain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/open_source_brain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Open Source Brain, a platform for sharing, viewing, analyzing, and simulating standardized models from different brain regions and species.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Model structure and parameters can be automatically visualized and their dynamical properties explored through browser-based simulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Infrastructure and tools for collaborative interaction, development, and testing are also provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open Source Brain contributors&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.opensourcebrain.org/">http://www.opensourcebrain.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Ankur Sinha (@ OSB/University College London)&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>DIPY</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/dipy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/dipy/</guid><description>&lt;p>DIPY is the paragon 3D/4D+ imaging library in Python. Contains generic methods for spatial normalization, signal processing, machine learning, statistical analysis and visualization of medical images. Additionally, it contains specialized methods for computational anatomy including diffusion, perfusion and structural imaging.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/dipy/dipy/graphs/contributors">https://github.com/dipy/dipy/graphs/contributors&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dipy.org">https://dipy.org&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnEuCRDGFOR5cfEo0nD3pw">https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnEuCRDGFOR5cfEo0nD3pw&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>OpenNeuro</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/openneuro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/openneuro/</guid><description>&lt;p>A free and open platform for sharing MRI, MEG, EEG, iEEG, and ECoG data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With OpenNeuro, you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Browse and explore public datasets and analyses from a wide range of global contributors. Our collection of public datasets continues to grow as more and more become BIDS compatible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download and use public data to create new datasets and run your own analyses.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Privately share your data so your colleagues can view and edit your work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Publish your dataset where anyone can view, download, and run analyses on it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create snapshots of your datasets to ensure past analyses remain reproducible as your datasets grow and change. Publish any of your snapshots while you continue work on your original data behind the scenes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Explore your published OpenNeuro dataset using BrainLife&amp;rsquo;s computing network. Utilize their community driven apps to run a variety of analysis and processing software in the browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Russell A. Poldrack; Krzysztof Jacek Gorgolewski&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://openneuro.org/">https://openneuro.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-video">Project Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FK_c1x1Pilk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FK_c1x1Pilk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Elizabeth DuPre&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>MNE-Python</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/mne-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/mne-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>MNE is a software package for processing electrophysiological signals primarily from magnetoencephalographic (MEG) and electroencephalographic (EEG) recordings, and more recently sEEG, ECoG and fNIRS. It provides a comprehensive solution for data preprocessing, forward modeling (with boundary element models), distributed source imaging, time–frequency analysis, non-parametric multivariate statistics, multivariate pattern analysis, and connectivity estimation. Importantly, this package allows all of these analyses to be applied in both sensor or source space. MNE is developed by an international team, with particular care for computational efficiency, code quality, and readability, as well as the common goal of facilitating reproducibility in neuroscience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Alexandre Gramfort;Eric Larson;Denis Engemann;Daniel Strohmeier;Christian Brodbeck;Roman Goj;Mainak Jas;Teon Brooks;Lauri Parkkonen;Matti Hämäläinen;Jaakko Leppakangas;Jona Sassenhagen;Jean-Rémi King;Daniel McCloy;Marijn van Vliet;Clemens Brunner;Chris Holdgraf;Martin Luessi;Joan Massich;Guillaume Favelier;Andrew R. Dykstra;Mikolaj Magnuski;Stefan Appelhoff;Britta Westner;Richard Höchenberger;Robert Luke;Luke Bloy;Thomas Hartmann;Olaf Hauk;Adam Li&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mne.tools">https://mne.tools&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Nilearn</title><link>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/nilearn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-neuroscience.com/post/nilearn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nilearn is a Python module for fast and easy statistical learning on NeuroImaging data. It leverages the scikit-learn Python toolbox for multivariate statistics with applications such as predictive modelling, classification, decoding, or connectivity analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-authors">Project Author(s)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/nilearn/people">https://github.com/orgs/nilearn/people&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-links">Project Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://nilearn.github.io/">http://nilearn.github.io/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This post was automatically generated by
Anonymous&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item></channel></rss>